EXECUTIVE SUMMARY AMITKUMAR SRIVASTAVA

(12th June 1973)

CAREER SUMMARY

I am professionally qualified, senior HR professional profile with over 24 years of experience across MNCs, Diversified Indian Business Groups, Private Equity & Consulting--the Corporate stint spanning diverse sectors like Diversified Groups IT Textiles[Blow room to Fish fabrics]/Apparel/Brands & Retail, Air-Conditioning, Chemicals and Pharmaceuticals[Formulation and API] Since 2009, I have been holding Head HR, IR and Administration senior positions at the national/global level for very large corporations and have established HR and IR practices in different Indian and International locations. I had an entrepreneurial stint; May 2017 I founded and have been running a successful Strategic HR and IR services firm. *And an honoured teacher in business and technology institutes.*

EXPOSURE:

- ✓ Functions
 - Manufacturing HR, IR:, HR Business Partnering, Plant HR, Industrial Relations, Legal Compliances, Social Compliance, Liasoning, Administration, Facility management, Business Operations.
 - Information Technologies HR: OSS, BSS, ISP, UTM, NSS, MFS, SI, Voice Wholesale Domains.
- ✓ Span of management Multi-locational 750 to 7000 white and blue collars
- √ National Locations Gujarat, Maharashtra, JnK, Karnataka, West Bengal, Delhi, Punjab
- ✓ <u>International Locations</u> USA, LATAM, ME, SEA, Africa.
- ✓ **Spearheaded** HR and IR vertical reporting to business heads.
- ✓ Hands-on working Experience of Traditional HR, Transactional HR, Transformational and Developmental HR
- ✓ <u>Industries</u> Large units of Textiles, Air-Conditioner, Chemical, Pharmaceuticals [Formulation and API] Information Technologies, Universities/Institutes.

KEY CAREER LEARNING HIGHLIGHTS:

- ✓ Strategic HR, ER and IR planning as per business objectives and execution.
- ✓ Organizational Restructuring, Reporting & Authority Matrix
- ✓ Goal Setting and cascading into individual KRAs/KPIs
- ✓ Talent Management– Multi geography, multi culture & level
- ✓ Performance management System aligned with Organization Goal
- ✓ High performing talent acquisition-National and International
- ✓ Training and Organizational Development Intervention
- ✓ Internal Competency building programmes.
- ✓ Designing Business Linked Employees Engagement , Reward and Recognition Programmes
- ✓ Employee Lifecycle Management Indian & International.
- ✓ Compensation Restructuring aligned with short and long term Business Goals
- ✓ Trade Union Management, Collective Bargaining, Wage Settlement [LTS/STS and troubleshooting.
- ✓ Government approval to run establishment, Statutory and Social Compliance Management and Liasoning.
- End to end Contract Labour Management, Manning norms and Shop floor discipline

SOME OF THE MAJOR PROJECTS EXECUTED DURING CONSULTING [cont..]

Career and Management Solutions is a young, boutique HR consulting firm I founded, providing HR and IR Advisory services to client companies and their Boards. In particular the firm offered a unique 'Director HR on hire' service. The firm specialized in working with medium to large India based family/promoter owned business groups.

Revamp Hiring Process Hiring at Middle and Senior levels	✓ Organization Re-Structuring And Right Sizing		
Training and Internal Competency Building Framework	Service Team Process improvement		
Business Goal Setting and KRAs Cascading	✓ Policies writing and implementation on Employee		
360 Degree Feedback System	Lifecycle Management		
Assessment Centre Formation	✓ Legal Compliance etc.		

M: +91 88 66 44 7869

Email: <u>akkumarcareer@gmail.com</u> <u>amitsrivastava18@hotmail.com</u>

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY AMITKUMAR SRIVASTAVA

(12th June 1973)

MAJOR CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS:

- ✓ Player pivotal role in Organizational Transformation to 18X business and sustained it.
- Established KRA and KPI driven work culture and brought objective based identification of performance and non-performance.
- ✓ Manpower Right Sized and rationalized by 25% Blue Collars and 11% Management level
- ✓ Brought organizational performance from 65% to 95% in 3.5 years.
- ✓ Achieved hiring target by 97% without external support of hiring agencies
- ✓ Reduced training expenses by 35% and increased 3 training Man days.
- ✓ Implemented Several Award Winning Shop Floor Interventions and Policies
- ✓ Implemented promotion policy based on acquired required competency to be in particular hierarchy.
- ✓ Formulated and implemented Internal Certification programme for Sales, Services, Production, RnD, Pre-sales, and Quality etc. found out competency delta of 33% and bridge the gap up to tolerance level.
- Established TAT and SLA based HR and Administration operations with escalation matrix.
- Ensured increasing trend in employee satisfaction index.

- ✓ Successfully handled local people agitation.
- ✓ Overall 2 green filed projects managed successfully starting from land acquisition to the commercial production within time span of 18 to 20 months.
- ✓ Reduces the employee cost by 16% with slight improvement in Top and Bottom lines.
- ✓ Achieved Zero Litigations
- ✓ Achieved Zero Man days loss due to labour unrest
- ✓ Achieved Zero Non-Compliances
- ✓ Managed the manufacturing of all the three shifts with Contract Labourers and achieved 98.8% Demand-Supply Metrics.
- ✓ Reduced Overtime by 80%
- ✓ 5 LTS with the Trade Unions amicably.
- ✓ Controlled Absenteeism from two digits to one digit
- ✓ Controlled Attrition from as high as 50% to 15% then to 10%
- ✓ Established and maintained 40 Offices in India and 11 offices at international Locations
- ✓ Managed Community relations with no dispute and won MD ward

M: +91 88 66 44 7869

✓ Reduced Cost per hire by 20%

COMPANIES WORK(ED)(ING) FOR:

ORGANIZATIONS	POSITIONS HELD	DURATION
Career and Management Solutions	Business Enabler- SMEs Self-Employed	May - 2017 till date
Panamax Infotech Limited	Head HR and Admin	June 2015 – May 2017
Elitecore (is now <u>Sterlite Tech. Ltd</u>) and Cyberoam Technology (is now <u>Sophos</u>)	Head HR and Admin	March 2011 - Dec-2014
Unimark Remedies Limited, Gujarat	DGM – HR and Admin	July 2009 - March 2011
Arvind Limited[Brands: Adidas, Reebok, MnS, JS, FM, BH]	Senior Manager - HR	Oct 2006 –July 2009
Hitachi Home & Life Solutions India Ltd,	Asst. Manager HR-IR	Dec 2002 - Oct 2006
Vardhman Acrylics Limited,	Dy. Executive - HR	June 1998 - Nov 2002
Core Healthcare Limited	Officer - Personnel	Jan- 1996 - May 1998

Email: <u>akkumarcareer@gmail.com</u> amitsrivastava18@hotmail.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY AMITKUMAR SRIVASTAVA

(12th June 1973)

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS:

DEGREE	CDECIALIZATION	INSTITUTES/
DEGREE	SPECIALIZATION	PASSING YEAR
Master's Degree in Social Work	■ Personnel Management and Industrial Relations	JK Institute, Lucknow,
	Labour Legislations and Welfare	India - 1995
Diploma in Business Administration	■ Industrial Psychology	
	■ Elements of Organization and Managements	NIIRD, Chennai, India–1997
	■ Labour Welfare and Labour Welfare Legislations	
Post Graduate Diploma in Business Administration[Distance Learning]	■ Strategic Management	
	 Organizational Behavior and Culture 	Symbiosis, Pune, India 2007
	OD and Training	Symbiosis, Pune, maia 2007
	■ Finance Management	

CERTIFICATIONS:

- ✓ Organizational Goal and KRA Setting Exercise
- ✓ Certified PPA (Personal Profile Analysis) Practitioner
- ✓ Train the Trainer Certified Trainer.
- ✓ Fire, Safety and Mock Drill.
- ✓ Domestic / Departmental Enquiry
- ✓ Estimating Manpower Requirement and Productive Redeployment.
- ✓ Workshop on Spearhead Youth Health Leadership Training for Youth in Sexual and Reproductive Health.

RECOGNITIONS & REWARDS:

- \checkmark Got appreciation mail from MD for managing Community relation.
- ✓ Garlanded by the workers' representatives.
- ✓ Verbal mentions for amicable settlements with the trade unions.
- ✓ Business Enabler Award for aligning entire Indian and International HR practices with the business goals.
- ✓ Award for Excellent Human Resources Hiring Practices.
- ✓ Award for Best Practice in Compensation Plan Restructuring.
- ✓ Award for Best Practices in Talent Acquisition.
- ✓ Got standing ovation from management team for establishing strong Business HR practices.
- ✓ Got Appreciation from MD for Rightsizing the Organization.
- ✓ Best HR Practice Execution Unit

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES:

- ✓ NCC (National Cadet Corps) "B" Certificate Holder. (Firing by 3030)
- ✓ NSS (National Service Scheme) Certificate Holder.
- ✓ Awarded a post of Cadet Captain, was leading a troop of 55 cadets.
- ✓ Played Cricket up to University level.
- ✓ Developed a slum under the project of Community development established primary school, imparted Sex education to all and awareness for health and hygiene etc.

AMIT SRIVASTAVA Ahmedabad

Email: <u>akkumarcareer@gmail.com</u> M: +91 88 66 44 7869

amitsrivastava18@hotmail.com